Contact

aavpedro@hotmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/antoniopedro1 (LinkedIn) about.me/antonio_pedro (Other)

Top Skills

Team Management Pre-sales

Team Leadership

Languages

French (Professional Working)
Spanish (Limited Working)
English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Developing Innovative Ideas for New Companies: The First Step in Entrepreneurship

António Pedro

Business Consultant

Lisbon Area, Portugal

Summary

I have Business and Technical IT Sector knowledge, focused on value added IT Infrastructures solutions, working in the Management, Business Development and Senior Consulting areas. A multi-functional experience in: Management, Business Development, Services Delivery Management, Project Management, Sales and Pre-sales. Worked for European multi-national companies, with contacts in a multi-cultural environment. Business development experience in different market sectors, namely: Public Administration, Health, Industry, Utilities and Distribution.

Specialties:

- IT Infrastructures
- Pre-sales
- Business and Operational Units Management
- Business Development
- Internal Quality Auditing
- Team management

Experience

Advantis Solutions Business Consultant April 2015 - Present

Mindbury Consulting
Manager
August 2014 - February 2015 (7 months)
Torres Vedras

Manager – Infrastructures Sector

Responsible for:

- Solutions and Services Offer Management
- Resources Coordination
- · Partnerships management

- Project Management based on PMI methodology
- New human resources selection
- Promoting continuous processes improvement aligned with best practices

Critical Center Director of Operations August 2014 - February 2015 (7 months)

Luanda, Angola

Responsible for:

- · Sales activities
- IT Infrastructure Solutions and Services Offer Management
- Resources Coordination
- · Partnerships management
- P&L management
- Project Management based on PMI methodology
- · Budget building
- · New human resources selection
- Promoting continuous processes improvement aligned with best practices

GFI Portugal

Infrastructures Manager

January 2010 - July 2012 (2 years 7 months)

I have coordinated the Infrastructures Projects and Maintenance Services
Team. Main tasks were: Business unit P&L Management, Supervising several
Projects Management, Budget preparation, Infrastructures Services Offer
coordination, Contact with Customers at pre-sales and delivery stages,
Contract management. Sales proposals elaboration and validation.

GFI Solutions

Infrastructures BU Manager

January 2008 - December 2009 (2 years)

I've managed the IT Infrastructures Business Unit achieving around 3 million euros of revenue on each year, between 2008 and 2009. I have coordinated the Infrastructures Projects and Maintenance Services Team. Responsible for the definition of all Infrastructure products and services offer, as well the respective delivery to customers.

Definition of annual budget, monthly monitoring of the evolution of Forecast and analysis of P&L

Supervising and participation on activities related with business generation, proposals preparation, presentation and negotiation

Resources planning and allocation supervision. Solution architectures definition. Follow projects implementation. Meetings with Customers for opportunities assessment. Maintenance and technical assistance contracts elaboration.

Partners management for complementing products and competencies offer. Continuous promotion for process improvements in accordance with the best practices. Definition of the policy and objectives of the Quality System and supervision of its accomplishment, as well contributing to its improvement.

Bull Portuguesa

8 years

Infrastructures & Maintenance Director January 2007 - December 2007 (1 year)

Lisboa

I've managed the Infrastructures & Maintenance Department, coordinating the Infrastructures Projects and Maintenance Services Team. Responsible for the definition of all Infrastructure products and services offer, as well the respective delivery to customers. End-to-end responsible for definition and implementation of Department's strategy and P&L, in accordance to the market and in coordination with General Management

Pre-sales Manager January 2003 - December 2006 (4 years)

Responsible for Pre-sales

Responsible for Servers, Unix and Storage Business Development

- · Business area offer organization
- Internal sales team training
- Responsible for IBM OEM offer
- Offer promotion to customers and prospects (presentations, support to Account Managers, press articles ...)
- Opportunities generation (campaigns, customers base, direct contacts, ...)
- Support on proposals elaboration
- Meetings with customers and prospects with respective Account Manager
- Partnerships management: Oracle, NEC, Informix, EMC
- Pre-sales project management

Sales Specialist & Product Manager January 2000 - December 2002 (3 years)

Bull Portuguesa Computadores Open Systems Pre-sales

January 1996 - December 1999 (4 years)

Open Systems Pre-sales Specialist

Bull Portuguesa Computadfores
Technical Sales Engineer
December 1989 - December 1995 (6 years 1 month)

Regindústria Systems Engineer 1988 - 1989 (1 year)

Education

Instituto Superior Técnico
Engineer, Electronic and Computers Engineering · (1980 - 1986)

EAP Ecole Européenne des Affaires - Paris European Potential Management Program · (1992 - 1993)

EuroForum Filipe II - Madrid Solution Selling® - Tom Robinson & Associates · (1998 - 1998)